A Guide to the Department of Conservation and Development, Division of History, Records, 1927-1950
Library of Virginia
- Series V. Historical Material, 1927-1950 (Accession 41571)
  - Henrico County (Richmond City, A-G) (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Henrico County (Richmond City, G-R) (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Henrico County (Richmond City, S-Z) (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Henrico County (A Portfolio of Old Richmond in Prints) (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Henry County (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Highland County (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Isle of Wight County (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - James City County (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - James City County (Information on Old Homes photographed by History Division) (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - James City County (Williamsburg) (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - James City County (Jamestown) (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - King and Queen County (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - King and Queen County (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division), A-L (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - King and Queen County (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division), M-W (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - King George County (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - King William County (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - King William County, (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division), A-D (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - King William County, (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division), E-N (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - King William County, (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division), O-W (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Lancaster County (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Lee County (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Loudoun County (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Loudoun County - Sergeant John Champe's File (Photostats of story taken from British United Service Journal) (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Louisa County (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Lunenburg County (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Madison County (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Mathews County (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Mecklenburg County (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Middlesex County (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous County Material, A thru J (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous County Material, K thru P/Q (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous County Material, R thru Z - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 101, Folder 10a)
  - Miscellaneous State Material, A to L (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous State Material, M to R (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous State Material, S to Z (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Montgomery County (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Nansemond County (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Nelson County (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - New Kent County (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - New Kent County (Information on Old House photographed by History Division), A-O (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - New Kent County (Information on Old House photographed by History Division), P-W (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Norfolk County (also includes Norfolk City) - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Northumberland County (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Nottoway County (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Orange County (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Page County (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Patrick County (Box 103, Folder 5a)
  - Pittsylvania County (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Powhatan County (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Prince Edward County - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Prince George County (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Prince William County (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Prince William County (First and Second Battles of Manassas) (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Princess Anne County (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Pulaski County (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Rappahannock County (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Roanoke County - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Rockbridge County (also includes Lexington) (part one) (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Rockbridge County (also includes Lexington) (part two) (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Rockingham County (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Russell County (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Scott County (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Shenandoah County (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Smyth County (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Southampton County (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Spotsylvania County (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Spotsylvania County (City of Fredericksburg) - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Stafford County - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Surry County (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Sussex County (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Tazewell County (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Warren County - See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 9 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Warwick County (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Washington County (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Westmoreland County (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Wise County (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Wythe County (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - York County (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - York County (Information on Old Houses photographed by History Division) (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Northern Neck of Virginia (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Southside Virginia - See Oversize Box 3, Folder 1
  - Southwest Virginia - See Oversize Box 3, Folder 2
  - Foreign Countries (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Garden Week in Virginia - See Oversize Box 3, Folder 3
  - Newspapers - See Oversize Box 3, Folder 4
  - Other States (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Other States (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Other States (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Daniel's File Index (Box 108)
- Oversize - Series I. Correspondence, 1927-1950 (accession 24806a)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1927-1950
    - Maps - various Virginia road maps (Map-case 24, Drawer 10)
    - Map of Norfolk and Western Railway and Connections, December 31, 1938 (Map-case 24, Drawer 10)
    - Richmond Battlefield Park (Fort Harrison Area) - map of Fort Harrison area, 10 August 1933; map of Richmond Battlefields, November 1930; map of 102.3 acres in Varina District, Henrico County, 27 February 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Battlefield Park (Fort Harrison Area) - sketch map of land conveyed to Geo. R. Harwood and wife by E.E. Booker, 27 September 1927; Monthly Progress report, Emergency Conservation Work, U.S. Dept. of Interior, November 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Battlefield Park (General File) (part one) - map of Richmond Battlefields, November 1930; proposed PWA project; (part two) - map of proposed Battlefield Parkway, April 1932; map of Gaines' Mill, 27 June 1862; map of Richmond showing various battlefields to be linked into a park system (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sampson, Mrs. Henry - Copy of Virginia Gazette and General Advertiser, 10 October 1792; Sanger, W.T. - Copy of Chicago Tribune, 12 February 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Shenandoah National Park (Newspaper Clippings, etc.) - copy of Northern Virginia Daily, section four, 27 November 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tapscott, K.A. (Assistant Landscape Architect) - Map of Trench Lines to Fort Brady, Richmond Battlefield Park, 23 May 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wakefield Restoration (George Washington clippings) - issue of The Colonial Interest, Colonial Beach, Virginia, 22 February 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wright Brothers (Mr. W.C. Hall's file) - issue of Washington Post Magazine, 17 November 1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence, Dead File, 1927-1950
    - American Automobile Association, Washington, DC (J.A. Brown, Business Manager) - two copies of Missouri Motor News (May 1936) and Official AAA Road Map for Maryland, Virginia, West Virginia and Delaware with handwritten annotations, nd (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Garden Week in Virginia Pamphlets - copy of Richmond Times Dispatch, 26 April 1942, section on Garden Week (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Spalding, Branch (National Park Service), 1933-1936 - hand drawn map by Branch Spalding of portion of Saylor's Creek Battlefield (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Virginia World War II History - two copies of The History of World War II compiled by the Associated Press (21 October 1945); 15 March 1945 issue of University of Virginia News Letter (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Oversize - Series II. Virginia War History Project, 1942-1946 (accession 24806b)
  - Subseries A: Counties
    - Henry County, 1944-1945 - casualty list(7 May 1945) and "Book of Letters to Service Men and Women" (25 November 1945) both from Martinsville Daily Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Montgomery County, 1942-1946 - Roll of Honor from unidentified newspaper, November 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Orange County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 - Orange County Honor Roll published in 14 March 1946 issue of The Orange Review (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Oversize - Series III. Graves of Distinguished Virginians Project, 1944-1948 (accession 24806c)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1944-1948
    - Graves of Distinguished Virginians - Work List - Marker Inscription for Thos. Savage (1595-1633) and Map of Hollywood Cemetery (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Howard, E.H. (Eastern Shore Marker Contract) - Marker Inscriptions for Chas. Scarborough (1643-1702), Obedience Robins (1600-1662), Col. Edmund Scarborough (1618-1671), Col. Wm. Kendall (died 1686), and Argol Yeardley (1621-1655) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Saunders - Swem (Sinclair, Jr., J.B.) - Elizabeth City County Zone Map, 28 May 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Oversize - Series IV. Records, 1929-1950 (accession 25913)
  - Subseries A: Reference Files
    - George Washington Bicentennial - United States George Washington Commission Clip Sheet, Numbers 15-21 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - George Washington Bicentennial - Potomac Interest, Westmoreland County Souvenir Edition, 22 February 1932; George Washington Bicentennial News published by Alexandria Gazette, June 1931 (2 copies) and August 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Oversize - Series V. Historical Material, 1927-1950 (Accession 41571)
  - Norfolk County (also includes Norfolk City) - sections B and K of Norfolk Virginian-Pilot, 75th Anniversary Edition, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Prince Edward County - section IV, March 1935 issue of The Farmville Herald (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous County Material, R thru Z - section on Virginia from 8 September 1935 issue of Brooklyn (NY) Daily Eagle (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Roanoke County - section two, 28 May 1938 of The Times-Register (Roanoke County centennial) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Spotsylvania County (City of Fredericksburg) - Washington Bicentennial section of 22 February 1932 issue of The Free Lance-Star (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stafford County - 23 July 1936 issue of The Stafford Register (reenactment of First Manassas) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Warren County - section eight, 27 November 1940 and section one, 15 November 1941 issues of Northern Virginia Daily (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Southside Virginia - 26 April 1934 issue of The Southside Virginia News; and supplement from 30 August 1940 Richmond News Leader on the National Tobacco Festival in South Boston (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Southwest Virginia - 30 August 1940 Sesqui-Centennial Edition of Southwest Virginia Enterprise (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Garden Week in Virginia - special supplement of The Richmond News Leader, 27 April 1936, 26 April 1937, 25 April 1938, 24 April 1939, 22 April 1940, 27 April 1941 and 24 April 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers - 30 November 1939 issue of The Richmond Times-Dispatch (Box 3, Folder 4)